(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone and
welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- My name is Catherine.
- And today we've got
part three of an exciting
series you got for you
at the elementary level.
- That's right.
As you may remember, this is a series that
we're studying all about a job interview.
So in the first part, we just
talked about the introduction.
The second part was talking
about your personal background
and now we're gonna talk about
your educational background.
- Okay, so the key topic here today
is education, let's take a listen to this
dialogue and we'll be back in a minute.
(upbeat music)
- Now if I look here, I see that
you completed a BA in English.
- Yes, that's right.
After graduating from high school in New
York, I attended York University in the UK.
My major was English
and my minor was business.
I completed my BA in 2004.
- Yes, I'm pleased to see
that you also got a distinction.
- Yes, that's right.
I've always enjoyed studying.
My friends say I'm a bit of a bookworm,
but my father always pushed
us to succeed at school.
- Well, it looks like his
encouragement paid off Rebecca.
So how about extra curricular
activities at university?
- Well, I've always been keen on writing,
so I became the editor for the university
student newspaper, which I really loved.
Also, I volunteered for a group called
Shelter to help the homeless in New York.
- What did that involve?
- Providing warm meals and shelter,
especially in the winter months.
I found it really fulfilling
to be part of that group.
- I'm sure.
Okay, now let's move on to
your work experience, shall we?
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back.
So the girl was talking about
her education, about her university,
and she talked about
some very interesting words.
So why don't we take a look
at those in language takeaway?
- Language takeaway.
So at the very beginning, Mr.
Parsons, who's the interviewer here,
asks Rebecca about her background
and says, "I see that you
completed your BA in English.
" - Okay, so we have an
acronym there, "Hey, BA.
"
This stands for bachelors,
or usually a four-year degree
at the beginning of
your university studies.
- That's right.
So it's a type of degree, right?
The BA is, as you say, your bachelor's
degree, and it usually takes four years.
- That's right, you have
the Bachelor of the Arts, BA,
but you also have a Bachelor
of Science, which is a BS.
So as you can tell, one is for the arts,
like art history, music, things like that.
The other is for sciences,
like physics or chemistry.
- Very good.
All right, so she has a BA in English,
so she obviously studied the
English language in university.
Then she moved on to talk
about her major and minor.
- That's right, so as you know, a degree is
not just a degree in the arts in general,
but it usually has a
focus or an area of focus.
So her area of focus,
her major was English.
This is the most important
part of her studies.
So many of her courses, most of her
courses, at university were in English.
- That's right, but she also
has a minor in business studies.
- Okay, that means she also
studied business and business studies.
That's not as important
as her English studies,
but it was very much
a part of her degree.
- So let's say that when she
was studying in university,
70% of what she studied was
related to her major English.
And maybe 30% was her
minor was business studies.
- That's right, and she
goes on to talk about herself
and her friends who
describe her as a bookworm.
This is a really nice adjective
and very common in English.
- That's right, so if you are
a bookworm or you describe
yourself as a bookworm, it
means that you like to study a like.
You like to read a lot of books.
- So bookworm is just like what you
said, is someone who really likes to read,
someone who's always reading,
maybe someone who lives in the library.
- So that's why you call them a bookworm.
They live in the library or
they read a lot of books.
All right, so that's the noun bookworm.
Now moving on to other parts of university,
when you're studying,
you're not only studying
English or sciences
and things like that.
Sometimes you also do
other activities or other things.
- That's right, so you have your schoolwork,
which is during school, it's English
and business studies
for this woman, Rebecca.
But you also have what
you do outside of school.
This is called extracurricular activities.
So that's a long word, extracurricular.
- That's right, so extracurricular
means it's not in the curriculum, right?
That's right, it's outside of school.
- So it's not really
like a specific subject
or something that's
related to your studies.
If you don't do extracurricular
activities, it's okay, right?
- That's right, a lot of people
don't do any extracurricular activities,
but many people do, for example, writing
for the school newspaper or playing soccer.
- Exactly, so those are
extracurricular activities.
Anything that you wanna do in university,
apart from studying, playing
soccer, writing, et cetera.
And it's not just university, you
can do these in high school as well.
- Okay, very good, so those are the words
that we have picked out for you today.
I think they're very specific to
education, and I think we should go back,
listen to the dialogue again, and we'll
be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
(upbeat music)
- Now if I look here, I see that
you've completed a BA in English.
- Yes, that's right.
After graduating from high school in New
York, I attended York University in the UK.
My major was English,
and my minor was business.
I completed my BA in 2004.
- Yes, I'm pleased to see
that you also got a distinction.
- Yes, that's right.
I've always enjoyed studying.
My friends say I'm a bit of a bookworm,
but my father always pushed
us to succeed at school.
- Well, it looks like his
encouragement paid off Rebecca.
So how about extracurricular
activities at university?
- Well, I've always been keen on writing,
so I became the editor for the university
student newspaper, which I really loved.
Also, I volunteered for a group called
Shelter to help the homeless in New York.
- What did that involve?
- Providing warm meals and shelter,
especially in the winter months.
I found it really fulfilling
to be part of that group.
- I'm sure.
Okay, now let's move on to
your work experience, shall we?
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
(upbeat music)
All right, we're back,
so now let's start
off with our first phrase
on fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
So Rebecca's talking about
her father and her friends,
and she says, she's a bookworm,
but her father always pushed us.
That means her and her family
members, her siblings, to succeed.
And this verb to push us, to
push someone is very important
because it's not the same
as like to push a door.
- Right, so it's not physically
that you're pushing somebody.
It's actually to motivate somebody
or to inspire someone to
become better at something.
- That's right.
So to push someone is to
encourage them to do something bad.
It's not always a good thing.
So she was always pushing
me to do what she wanted to do.
Not what I wanted to do.
That means someone's always trying to
influence you or to get you to do something.
- Exactly.
So as you say, to push
someone is to influence them,
to motivate them, to encourage
them to do something good or bad.
Well, and Mr. Parsons
agreed with her dad's
encouragement, and he
said, well, it really paid off.
- Okay, this is a great
verbal phrase to pay off.
This means to have benefits.
Okay, so all of your
hard work really paid off.
- So you can see the results.
You can see the positive
results of your hard work.
It paid off.
- You could even ask someone.
All that hard work, did it pay off?
- Right.
So that you're basically
asking, was it worth it?
- Yeah.
- Okay, to pay off.
And well, when she was
talking about extracurricular
activities, she said she
was always keen on writing.
- Now, I think this is more
common among British people
to say you're keen on something,
but it basically means to like.
So remember the phrase keen on.
This is the preposition here, keen on.
I'm keen on writing.
- So can you say that
you are keen on someone?
- Yes, you can.
That means you like
someone, maybe romantically.
- Okay, so it's kind of, as Catherine said,
a more of a British
thing, but it's correct,
and you can use it in
replacement of to like.
- I think it also sounds
a little bit more formal
instead of saying, well,
I've always liked writing.
If she says, well, I've always been
keen on writing, I think it sounds nice.
- Well, smarter.
- Yeah, all right, and our last word,
it's actually an interesting word.
It might be a little bit complicated
to understand, but when she said that,
but when she said that volunteering was
very fulfilling and to be part of a group.
- Okay, fulfilling sounds
a lot like the word filling,
but you shouldn't confuse these two because
the meaning is very different, right?
So something that is fulfilling
makes you feel really good.
You maybe you don't make money from it,
or you don't get a lot of praise from it,
but it still makes you feel happy
about life for yourself or something.
- So you get satisfaction.
Now, notice the pronunciation.
You don't say full filling.
- No, you say fulfilling, fulfilling.
So the L there is kind
of silent, kind of optional.
But maybe you could ask someone,
what do you find fulfilling in your life?
- Uh-huh.
- Or you can ask, do you
think your job is fulfilling?
- Yeah, okay.
So a lot of great words
there, a lot of interesting
things related to
education, and not so much.
- Why don't we go back and
listen to the dialogue one last time?
- Now, if I look here, I see that
you completed a BA in English.
- Yes, that's right.
After graduating from high school in New
York, I attended York University in the UK.
My major was English,
and my minor was business.
I completed my BA in 2004.
- Yes, I'm pleased to see
that you also got a distinction.
- Yes, that's right.
I've always enjoyed studying.
My friends say I'm a bit of a bookworm,
but my father always pushed
us to succeed at school.
- Well, it looks like his
encouragement paid off Rebecca.
So how about extra curricular
activities at university?
- Well, I've always been keen on writing,
so I became the editor for the university
student newspaper, which I really loved.
Also, I volunteered for a group called
Shelter to help the homeless in New York.
- What did that involve?
- Providing warm meals and shelter,
especially in the winter months.
I found it really fulfilling
to be part of that group.
- I'm sure.
Okay, now let's move on to
your work experience, shall we?
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so talking
about going to university,
I think they used a really specific
verb there that's worth mentioning.
She said I attended
York University in the UK.
So to attend.
- That's right, so you can
say I studied at York University,
but the more formal way
of saying that I was a student
at York University is to
say I attended that school.
So to attend means to
be a student at that place.
- Okay, and what about you, Katherine?
Did you participate in any extra
curricular activities back in college?
- I did, I participated in a lot
of extra curricular activities.
I was in the orchestra in my university
and I played in a lot of musical groups.
I also was in a discussion group for politics
and the India-Pakistan dialogue group.
And I was in a number
of different film clubs.
So we talk about film and I even helped
out at the TV station for my university.
- Oh wow, the university had a TV station.
- Yeah, so all of it was student-directed.
So basically the students
controlled the TV station.
- That's really interesting.
I think these types of
extra curricular activities
are as many as these
are maybe not as common
in other places or maybe
they're a little bit different.
I know, for example, in
the US, you have all these
political ones and a lot of
sports and things like that.
But you also have very strange,
far ones like, I don't know,
like there's a cooking club
and there's even like a gardening club or astronomy club.
- Astronomy club.
There's all types of
extra curricular activities.
- Well, what's really nice about
a lot of American universities
is that there are many, many
resources that students can use.
And so maybe the reason there's a cooking
club is because there are massive kitchens
the students can use to
cook food and experiment
and even teachers and
professors sometimes come to help.
So it's a really nice environment
because everyone's teaching each other.
- Right, no, it's very, very interesting.
And we're actually curious to know
how universities work in your country.
Are you able to have a minor in a subject
because many universities
don't offer this option?
- Right, they just have
one major in that talk.
- Right, or maybe are you able to
participate in extra curricular activities?
- Like sports or radio
or writing, let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
- All right, so we'll see you guys there.
- Bye. - Bye.
(upbeat music)